<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>NAP - Novels and Physics</title>
  
  
  <link href="https://pobmaner.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://pobmaner.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-24T17:36:30.161Z</updated>
  <id>https://pobmaner.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>LS</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Endless Journey</title>
    <link href="https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/25/travel/"/>
    <id>https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/25/travel/</id>
    <published>2025-08-24T16:38:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-08-24T17:36:30.161Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="endless-journey"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#endless-journey"></a> Endless Journey</h1><p>Rostky was born in an obscure little town, which was unprecedentedly prosperous when he was a child. Clean marble was used to build chess tables, and newborn piglets and lambs were given names by children or wandering poets. However, by the time he was twenty, all of this existed only in his memories. The chess tables had been dismantled and sold for money, and the remaining livestock could no longer provide for new life. Neighbors had no interest in celebrating any holidays, and most of the town’s casinos and taverns had closed down. People had nothing to talk about, and most of them couldn’t even use the Common Era to explain where they were in history. The most talked about topics were still the chickens, ducks, geese, and sheep at home. They would talk about how to raise these livestock, citing classical texts with solemn seriousness, from the veterinarian’s “General Principles of Animal Husbandry” to Aristotle’s treatise on irrational numbers; Today, there are few people left who still raise livestock at home, and most people no longer have the qualifications to engage in lively discussions at the tavern, instead returning home to engage in so-called idle speculation.<br />A wandering poet once composed a verse for this nameless small town: “Prosperous places are all alike, but each decaying one is decaying in its own way.” This sparked a craze at the time, and people gathered again in the tavern to discuss the uniqueness of this place’s decay. Some stinking old men brought up history dating back hundreds of years, and even the souls of the dead in the graveyard became their arguments. literary enthusiasts analyzed every word, with each character warranting pages of analysis and commentary. Rotszki emerged from this farce having left his childhood behind; he believed he had encountered his life mentor, the owner of the town’s only bookstore: Old Man McLeod. This old man had not left his dilapidated store since his youth, yet during that time he stayed out all night, passionate and enthusiastic, delivering impassioned speeches at the bar like a child, expressing his views. Rostky was immediately drawn to his flowing white hair, and years later, he still couldn’t forget the first thing he said when they met: “Your brain will one day shrink and disappear because it’s full of water.” At the time, he was yelling at a middle school student.<br />When everyone finally went home, Rostky became a regular at the bookstore. He believed that the old man’s words were completely different from those of others, and his logic was unique, like that of God.<br />When everyone finally went home, Rotsky became a regular at the bookstore. He believed that the old man’s words were completely different from those of other people, his logic was unique and omnipotent like God’s, and his vocabulary was as varied as that of the famous critic Goethe. Some say that the history of this store is longer than that of the village’s meteorite, and the owner even traces it back further; after all, he was born in a certain place and went on to establish this store. The old man just smiled and said nothing. The days in the bookstore are so leisurely that he has left his footprints in the messy piles of books. The Latin books written by the ancient Greek patriarch and the Chinese eunuch’s writings, hidden in the deepest corners, have been brought back to life because of him. He made a few close friends, all regulars at the bookstore. They often talked day and night, arguing endlessly over an idea or an article, as if the farce had never stopped, those lives had never grown old, that splendor had never faded, and that journey had never ended.<br />One day, one of his friends excitedly announced some news: he had won second prize in the lottery and received a ticket that could be used indefinitely. Rotsky traded his property and five pieces of gold for the ticket and boarded the train for an endless journey. He sat by the window; there were few people in the carriage. He saw the rapeseed flowers in full bloom in June; an old woman tending the fields shouted angrily at the train, waking her from her nap; female students returning to school posed by the pond, drawing frequent glances from passengers; The surrounding Milocca Forest was once again bypassed, with huge trees looming over the train tracks. Occasionally, someone would ask him where the final destination was, and he would reply, “Amipetis.” When would they arrive? Perhaps today, or yesterday; no one knew.<br />Years later, facing the Milocca Jungle, Roztki would recall that evening when he met Maile.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
        
        
    <summary type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;endless-journey&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor&quot; href=&quot;#endless-journey&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Endless Journey&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rostky was born in an obscure</summary>
        
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/16/hello-world/"/>
    <id>https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/16/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T17:42:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-08-24T17:24:43.280Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome!</p><p>This website is used to record some original novels for entertainment purposes. These novels will not be published, they will only be recorded and viewed here.</p><p>At the same time, this website also records messy information about physics, mathematics, and computers. You may not find what you are looking for, but when you are bored and want to find some related fun things, this may be a good place.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
        
        
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website is used to record some original novels for entertainment purposes. These novels will not be published, they</summary>
        
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Related issues regarding the fastest descent line</title>
    <link href="https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/16/ins/"/>
    <id>https://pobmaner.github.io/2025/08/16/ins/</id>
    <published>2025-08-15T17:42:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2025-08-20T04:21:56.012Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="question-background"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#question-background"></a> Question background</h2><p>Regardless of resistance, what curve takes the shortest time for a point to move from one point to another in a vertical plane? In 1697, John Bernoulli provided the solution to the steepest descent line problem.<br />Now there is a circle, and at any point on it, when the circle rolls purely once on the ground, the trajectory of this point is called a cycloid. Cycloid is also the solution to the problem of the steepest descent line.</p><h3 id="deduction-of-parameter-equations"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#deduction-of-parameter-equations"></a> Deduction of Parameter Equations</h3><p>$$v &#x3D; \frac{ds}{dt}$$</p><p>$$ds &#x3D; \sqrt{1+y^{&#39;2}} dx$$</p><p>$$v &#x3D; \sqrt{2gy}$$</p><p>$$dt &#x3D; \frac{ds}{v}$$</p><p>$$t_{min}&#x3D;\int_0^{x_0}{\frac{\sqrt{1+y^{&#39;2}}}{\sqrt{2gy}}}dx$$</p><p>The solution using variational method is：</p><p>$$x&#x3D;c(\theta-sin\theta)$$</p><p>$$y&#x3D;c(1-cos\theta)$$</p><p>The coefficient is determined by the target coordinates</p><h2 id="thought-questions1"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#thought-questions1"></a> Thought questions1</h2><p>Question: What curve does a homogeneous disk with a radius of R roll purely along, and does it descend the fastest?<br />Provide the equation for the “steepest descent line” of a disk.</p><p><img src=".%5Cins_0.png" alt="" /></p><p>The kinetic energy is the sum of translational kinetic energy and rotational kinetic energy：</p><p>$$T&#x3D;\frac{1}{2}mv^2+\frac{1}{2}Jw^2$$</p><p>and $J&#x3D;\frac{1}{2}mR^2$, pure rolling condition$v=wR$，we can get</p><p>$$T&#x3D;\frac{3}{4}mv^2$$</p><p>so $v&#x3D;\sqrt{\frac{4}{3}gy}$</p><p>$$t_{min}&#x3D;\int_0^{x_0}{\frac{\sqrt{1+y^{&#39;2}}}{\sqrt{\frac{4}{3}  gy}}}dx$$</p><p>Due to the only difference in coefficients, using the same variational method as the first part of the derivation, the result obtained is still a cycloid.Set the cycloid with a downward direction as the center trajectory, and set the parameter equation to the following form:：</p><p>$$x&#x3D;R(\theta-sin\theta)$$</p><p>$$y&#x3D;-R(1-cos\theta)$$</p><p>In order to obtain the true trajectory curve, that is, the disk descends along such a curve, a method is first proposed, which calculates the normal direction of each point of the cycloid at the center of the circle, and extends the length of a radius in that direction, which is the desired curve. This method has no mathematical expression and can be used to compare the calculated trajectory with the theoretical trajectory in the animation<br />Now derive the theoretical trajectory. The angle between the cycloid tangent of the center trajectory and the horizontal line is $\gamma $ . First, calculate the tangent</p><p>$$\frac{dy}{dx}&#x3D;\frac{dy}{d\theta}\frac{d\theta}{dx}&#x3D;-\frac{sin\theta}{1-cos\theta}$$</p><p>Assuming $\gamma $ is an acute angle, then</p><p>$$tan\gamma&#x3D;\frac{sin\theta}{1-cos\theta}$$</p><p>obtain</p><p>$$sin\gamma&#x3D;\frac{sin\theta}{\sqrt{2-2cos\theta}}&#x3D;cos\frac{\theta}{2}$$</p><p>$$cos\gamma&#x3D;\frac{1-cos\theta}{2sin\frac{\theta}{2}}&#x3D;sin\frac{\theta}{2}$$</p><p>Let the coordinates of the desired trajectory line be $x^{&#39;},y^{&#39;}$</p><p>$$x^{&#39;}&#x3D;x-Rsin\gamma$$</p><p>$$y^{&#39;}&#x3D;y-Rcos\gamma$$</p><p>obtain</p><p>$$x^{&#39;}&#x3D;R(\theta-sin\theta-cos\frac{\theta}{2})$$</p><p>$$y^{&#39;}&#x3D;-R(1-cos\theta+sin\frac{\theta}{2})$$</p><p>This parameter equation is the required curve equation. Note that the parameters of the cycloid equation for the center of the circle can be set according to the target point. Setting the above derivation as $R$ is only for convenience. The program simulates the surface calculation trajectory to coincide with the theoretical trajectory, which has been demonstrated in the animation<br />To ensure the authenticity of the animation demonstration, a derivation of $\theta$ with respect to time $t$ is made. Firstly, the parameter equation is assumed to be as follows:</p><p>$$x&#x3D;R(\theta-sin\theta)$$</p><p>$$y&#x3D;R(1-cos\theta)$$</p><p>$$t_{x_0}&#x3D;\int_0^{x_0}{\frac{\sqrt{1+y^{&#39;2}}}{\sqrt{\frac{3}{4}  gy}}}dx&#x3D;\int_0^{\theta}{\frac{\sqrt{(dx)^2+(dy)^2}}{\sqrt{\frac{3}{4}gy}}}$$</p><p>Processing molecules：</p><p>$$\sqrt{(dx)^2+(dy)^2}&#x3D;d\theta\sqrt{(\frac{dx}{d\theta})^2+(\frac{dy}{d\theta})^2}&#x3D;\sqrt{2}R\sqrt{1-cos\theta}$$</p><p>$$t(\theta)&#x3D;\int_{0}^{\theta}\frac{\sqrt{2}R\sqrt{1-cos\theta}}{\sqrt{\frac{4}{3}}R\sqrt{1-cos\theta}}d\theta&#x3D;\sqrt{\frac{3R}{2g}}\theta$$</p><p>Here, only the first half is taken, which is $\theta \in [0, \pi] $. For the second half, it is considered symmetrical to the first half. During the animation demonstration, $\theta $ is adjusted to be a function proportional to the frame rate</p><h2 id="thought-questions2"><a class="markdownIt-Anchor" href="#thought-questions2"></a> Thought questions2</h2><p>Assuming that the angle between the velocity direction of the disk and the seeding direction is $\alpha$, and the angle between the cycloid tangent of the center trajectory and the horizontal line is $\ gamma $, then the two are complementary to each other.Assuming the static sliding friction coefficient is $\mu$.Consider a downward cycloid as the center trajectory：</p><p>$$x&#x3D;c(\theta-sin\theta)$$</p><p>$$y&#x3D;-c(1-cos\theta)$$</p><p>Firstly, consider a feasible initial position where the velocity is zero, identify the critical condition for the disk to slide, and consider $f&#x3D;\mu F_N$</p><p>$$mgsin\alpha&#x3D;F_N$$</p><p>$$mgcos\alpha-f&#x3D;ma$$</p><p>$$a&#x3D;\beta R$$</p><p>$$fR&#x3D;\frac{1}{2}mR^2\beta$$</p><p>obtain</p><p>$$tan\alpha&#x3D;\frac{1}{3\mu}$$</p><p>The following needs to be solved using $\gamma$：</p><p>$$\frac{dy}{dx}&#x3D;\frac{dy}{d\theta}\frac{d\theta}{dx}&#x3D;-\frac{sin\theta}{1-cos\theta}&#x3D;-\frac{1}{tan\frac{\theta}{2}}&#x3D;-tan\gamma&#x3D;-\frac{1}{tan\alpha}&#x3D;-3\mu$$</p><p>$$tan\frac{\theta}{2}&#x3D;\frac{1}{3\mu}$$</p><p>$$\theta&#x3D;2arctan\frac{1}{3\mu}$$</p><p>because of $\theta\in[0,2\pi]$，the non sliding range obtained is：</p><p>$$\theta \in [2arctan\frac{1}{3\mu},2\pi-2arctan\frac{1}{3\mu}]$$</p><blockquote><p>The correct answer is obtained here. Due to the author’s seemingly more complex analysis, other major difficulties arose later. The subsequent proof is for reference only. If readers find any errors, they can contact me. The previous process should have been correct.</p></blockquote><p>Next, it needs to be proven that placing a disk at any position in this area does not slide during the cycle. Here, it only needs to be proven that it can be achieved at the critical position. However, in other positions, due to energy conservation, the velocity at each point is lower than the already proven case, and the centripetal inertial force is small. Therefore, it can be proven that the same holds true. We will not go into detail here</p><p>Under critical conditions，$tan\alpha&#x3D;\frac{1}{3\mu}$</p><p>$$f≤\mu F_N$$</p><p>$$mgsin\alpha&#x3D;F_N+\frac{mv^2}{\rho}$$</p><p>Here $\rho$ is curvature radius</p><p>In the end, we need to prove</p><p>$$\frac{1}{3}gcos\alpha\leq \mu gsin\alpha-\frac{v^2}{\rho}$$</p><p>that is</p><p>$$F(\alpha)&#x3D;\frac{1}{3}gcos\alpha-\mu gsin\alpha+\frac{v^2}{\rho}\leq 0,\alpha \in[arctan\frac{1}{3\mu},\frac{\pi}{2}]$$</p><p>$v$  is a function of  $\alpha$<br />Firstly, it is necessary to obtain the curvature radius</p><p>$$\rho&#x3D;|\frac{ds}{d\alpha}|&#x3D;\frac{\sqrt{(dx)^2+(dy)^2}}{\frac{1}{2}d\theta}&#x3D;\frac{d\theta\sqrt{(\frac{dx}{d\theta})^2+(\frac{dy}{d\theta})^2}}{\frac{1}{2}d\theta}&#x3D;4csin\frac{\theta}{2}$$</p><p>immersion</p><p>$$\frac{1}{2}sin\theta-\frac{3}{2}\mu+\frac{3}{2}\mu cos\theta-cos\theta +cos\theta_0\leq0$$</p><p>Try to prove that the above equation holds for $\theta_0&#x3D;2arctan3 \mu $, and take the derivative on the left side</p><p>$$G&#39;(\theta)&#x3D;\frac{1}{2}cos\theta-(\frac{3}{2}u-1)sin\theta$$</p><p>It was found that $G &#39;(\theta_0) \leq0 $ is equivalent to $9u ^ 2-12u+1 \geq 0 $. This equation depends on the value of the static friction coefficient, which means that there exists a static friction coefficient that causes it to slide. Therefore, this conclusion does not hold, and the actual range should be smaller than the initial placement range<br />Attempt to make $G &#39;(\theta_0)&#x3D;0 $ for any static friction coefficient, where the parameter should be a critical parameter. As long as it is proven that this range does not slip under the critical parameter, the range of parameter values can be determined by it</p><p>$$tan\theta_0&#x3D;\frac{1}{3\mu -2}$$</p><p>$$G&#39;&#39;(\theta)&#x3D;-\frac{1}{2}sin\theta-(\frac{3}{2}u-1)cos\theta$$</p><p>when $u&lt;\frac{2}{3},cos\theta&lt;0$</p><p>$$tan\theta \leq 0 &lt;2-3\mu$$</p><p>then</p><p>$$G&#39;&#39;(\theta)\leq 0$$</p><p>then:</p><p>when $u&gt;\frac{2}{3}$</p><p>For the portion of  $cos \theta \geq0 $</p><p>we can see</p><p>$$(2-3\mu)cos\theta&lt;sin\theta$$</p><p>that is</p><p>$$G&#39;&#39;(\theta)\leq 0$$</p><p>For the portion of  $cos\theta\leq0$</p><p>we can see</p><p>$$cos\theta&lt;(3\mu-2)sin\theta$$</p><p>that is</p><p>$$G&#39;(\theta)\leq 0$$</p><p>In conclusion</p><p>$$G&#39;(\theta)\leq 0$$</p><p>It can be proved.</p><p>when $u&#x3D;\frac{2}{3}$，most of the proofs are similar to the latter half of $u&gt;\frac{2}{3}$</p><p>Get $\theta$  at this moment</p><p>$$\theta_0&#x3D;arctan\frac{1}{3\mu-2}$$</p><p>那么</p><p>$$\theta \in [arctan\frac{1}{3\mu-2},2\pi-arctan\frac{1}{3\mu-2}]$$</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
        
        
    <summary type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;question-background&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;markdownIt-Anchor&quot; href=&quot;#question-background&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Question background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of</summary>
        
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
